Francesco is a drama, history film directed by Liliana Cavani.
The life of St.
Francis of Assisi (1181-1226) as related by followers who gather after his death to tell stories so that Leone can record them: a privileged and virile youth, a prisoner of
war, an heir who turns away from his father and gives all to the poor, a beggar for others, and an inspiration to friends who accept the Gospels' life of poverty.
Francesco, played by Mickey Rourke.
Chiara, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Francesco's Mother, played by Andréa Ferréol.
Cardinal Colonna, played by Nikolaus Dutsch.
Bishop Guido, played by Peter Berling.
Pope Innocent III, played by Hanns Zischler.
Francesco is a 1989 historical drama film about the life of St.
Francis of Assisi.
It is directed and co-written by Liliana Cavani, and stars Mickey Rourke
as Francis and Helena Bonham Carter as the future St.
The screenplay is adapted from Hermann Hesse’s 1904 book Francis of Assisi.
Vangelis composed the musical score.
The film won three awards and was nominated for a fourth.
Danilo Donati won the 1989 David di Donatello Award for Best Production Design, and the 1989 Italian
National Syndicate of Film Journalists Silver Ribbon also for Best Production Design.
Fabio Bussotti won the Syndicate's Best Supporting Actor Award.
Director Liliana Cavani was nominated for the Golden
Palm at the 1989 Cannes Film Festival.
The film is the second of three works by Cavani about St.
Francis, preceded by a 1966 telefilm starring Lou Castel in the title
role, and a 2014 production with Mateusz Kościukiewicz.
The film explores themes of christianity, religion,
saint, woman director, 13th century.
The tone is emotional.